Guide to the Harry W. Cox Papers, 1948-1977 (bulk 1962-1976)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Harry W. Cox papers 1948-1977 (bulk 1962-1976)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Cox, Harry W., 1904-1983
7.2 Linear Feet 5,400 Items
The holdings within this collection are from the files of Harry W. Cox, accountant to Duke Farms throughout the 1960s and 1970s. The topics in this collection are widely varied although they are primarily focused on the personal and business accounting activities of Doris Duke, her estates, and her charitable foundations. Materials included are business correspondence and memoranda, tax returns, invoices, contracts, bills, and legal documents.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research, however there are restrictions on certain materials within the collection. See Series level descriptions for more information.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Harry W. Cox Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a donation from the Doris Duke Charitable Foundation in June 2009.
Collection Overview
The Harry W. Cox Papers (formerly MSS.003) are part of the Doris Duke Charitable Foundation Historical Archives which were donated to the Duke University David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library by the Doris Duke Charitable Foundation. The collection spans the years 1948 to 1977, although the majority of the collection is concentrated in the years 1962 to 1976. The holdings within this collection are from the files of Harry W. Cox, accountant to Duke Farms throughout the 1960s and 1970s. The topics in this collection are widely varied although they are primarily focused on the personal and business accounting activities of Doris Duke, her estates, and her charitable foundations. Materials included are business correspondence and memoranda, tax returns, invoices, contracts, bills, and legal documents. The materials in this collection were originally arranged by the Doris Duke Charitable Foundation and the arrangement has been retained.
Duke, Doris, 1912-1993
Cox, Harry W., 1904-1983
Related Material
Doris Duke Papers, 1798-2003
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Doris Duke Papers on the Duke Farms Residence, 1859-2004 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Doris Duke Papers on the Falcon Lair Residence, 1937-1999
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Doris Duke Papers on the Shangri La Residence, 1932-2003
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Doris Duke Papers on the Rough Point Residence, 1922-1997
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke Gardens Foundation Records, 1912-2002
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Newport Restoration Foundation Records, 1968-1999
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Ibrahim Farrah Papers, 1895-1998
Dance Heritage Coalition
Contents of Collection
- Administrative Records, 1948-1977
  RESTRICTED: Access to several folders in boxes 2, 3, and 4 are restricted and require prior written approval from the Doris Duke Charitable Foundation to view.
  - Correspondence and memoranda regarding accounting of The Animal Medical Center, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Donations to The Animal Medical Center, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Invoices billed to The Animal Medical Center in error, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Donation of 1929 Chevrolet "American La France" fire engine to The Animal Medical Center, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Monthly lease for The Animal Medical Center, 1972–1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence and memoranda regarding distribution of salaries between Duke Farms and The Animal Medical Center, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and reports regarding financial and tax matters of the Doris Duke Foundation, 1974–1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Grants and donations made to various organizations by the Doris Duke Foundation. Includes figures of income and expenditures for Doris Duke, 1970–1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Details of stock transactions, transcripts of Custody Principal and Income Accounts, statements of investment, and CPA memoranda,1970–1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letter addressed to Pete Cooley from Wesley Fach outlining properties owned by Doris Duke, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Summary of invoices for Somerville, New York, Honolulu, and Beverly Hills retailers, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Notes receivable ledgers and certain non-employee loans, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Memorandum regarding regular monthly bills not requiring approval, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Inventory of missing items at Duke Farms as a result of burglary, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Organizational chart at Duke Farms, circa 1970s (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence confirming receipt of pension checks to former Duke employees, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - General correspondence regarding Duke Employees Pension Plan, 1967–1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Report (2 copies) authored by Towers, Perrin, Forster & Crosby, Inc. entitled "Pension Plan for Duke Employees/Actuarial Report as of January 1, 1971." Includes blank evaluation forms authored by Morgan Guaranty Trust Company, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence regarding general personnel topics such as retirements, federal programs affecting salary (the Economic Stabilization Program), salary increases, and salary billing, 1968–1973 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Records and correspondence concerning dismissed employees, 1957-1973 (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Access restricted
  - Records and correspondence concerning dismissed employees, 1957-1973 (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Business reports, requisition and billing correspondence, 1970–1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and memoranda regarding various contracts including installation of alarm systems, fountain pump, and paving at Duke Farms, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and memoranda related to a variety of contracts for the upkeep and security of Duke Farms, 1971-1973 (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence and memoranda related to a variety of contracts for the upkeep and security of Duke Farms, 1971-1973 (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Duke Farms Business Report for Month of December 1973, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - License copies and correspondence for the Heliport at Duke Farms, 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Verification of donations granted to the Duke Gardens Foundation, 1970–1971 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence regarding authorization for the payment of bills and invoices sent to Duke Farms, 1971–1972 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence regarding proposed contract for repairs at Rough Point estate, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Sample purchase order, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Duke Farms weekly business reports from week ending August 7, 1970 through week ending December 1, 1973, 1970–1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and application regarding visit to Sikkim, India, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Memoranda and correspondence concerning Duke Employees Pension Plan, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Application for Patricia Phair to be authorized as a N.J. Notary Public, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and memoranda regarding various personnel related topics, including salary billing, job descriptions on an individual basis, and salary increases, 1962-1975 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence related to Duke Farms security, 1970, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Contracts, bills, and correspondence pertaining to the reconstruction and restoration of the Chinese Garden and the Desert Garden at Duke Farms. Includes a solar energy survey and recommendation, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Contract with Lord & Burnham for Edwardian Garden reconstruction, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Contracts, bills, and correspondence pertaining to the reconstruction and restoration of the greenhouse complex and Italian Garden, 1971-1975 (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Contracts, bills, and correspondence pertaining to the reconstruction and restoration of the greenhouse complex and Italian Garden, 1971-1975 (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Contract with Lord & Burnham for reconstruction of Semi-Tropical Garden and Colonial Garden, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Contracts, bills, and correspondence pertaining to the reconstruction and restoration of the Semi-Tropical Garden, Edwardian Garden, Italian Garden, and Colonial Garden, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and memoranda regarding various personnel matters including salary reviews and recommendations, salary increase worksheets, retirements, and salary billing clarifications, 1972–1973 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Bills and invoices sent to Falcon Lair, 1969–1970 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Requests for employment and notices of salary increments, 1962–1967 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence and memoranda regarding the finances and various accounts of the Foundation for Southeast Asian Art & Culture (SEAAC), 1969–1975 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Invoices from Sears, Sheridan companies, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Sale of Haiku Valley, appraisal of Kaneohe property, and appraisal of Halekou Road property. Includes correspondence with Omni Corporation, Eaton Van Winkle & Greenspoon, and Vincent H. Yano, Esq., 1970–1972 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Documents outlining the dismantled Thai village which was housed on docks in Honolulu for an extended period of time. Includes photocopies of article, 1962–1972 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - SEAAC claim against Walker P. Inman, Jr. for accidental fire of Thai House, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Unsolicited offers addressed to SEAAC for the sale of items for its collection. Both offers declined, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence and memoranda regarding various SEAAC personnel matters, including guards for SEAAC property, pension concerns, and the retirement of Webber and Wiegand, 1969-1973 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Near East Dance Foundation Analysis of disbursements, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Near East Dance Foundation Analysis of personal checks signed by Doris Duke, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Near East Dance Foundation Disbursements excluding payroll, 1971–1972 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Documents regarding the finance and quality of the Near East Dance Foundation, including notes on insurance, receipts and disbursements, income and expenses, notes on storage room, unpaid invoices, costume inventory, and detail of checks. Includes chiffon cloth samples, 1972–1975 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and notes regarding the Near East Dance Foundation. Includes meeting notes, notes on film starring Nadia Gamal, and correspondence with Mounir Maassri, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Financial documents primarily regarding the Near East Dance Foundation. Includes case-by-case billing, and receipts from research trip to Lebanon by Doris Duke and Robert Farrah, 1972-1975 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Near East Dance Foundation Statements of Income and Expenditure, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence regarding the changing of Near East Dance Foundation officers, including resignation of Robert Farrah, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Ledgers and summaries for personnel of the Near East Dance Foundation, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Weekly payroll for Near East Dance Foundation, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Robert Farrah's Journal. Includes description of methodology and finances during Farrah’s tenure with the Near East Dance Foundation, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - 1970 Grant from Doris Duke Foundation to the Newport Restoration Foundation, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Memorandum concerning plants from Duke Parks billed to Newport Restoration Foundation, labor performed by NRF at Rough Point, and operating expenses, 1971, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Documents pertaining to the donation of Prescott Farms property to the Newport Restoration Foundation, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence concerning the transfer of Farewell Street property in exchange for property on the corner of Walnut and Second Streets in Newport, R.I., 1969–1970 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Letter from potential buyer, expressing interest in real estate to be used for parking lot for Newport Restoration Foundation, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Slater Report: Doris Duke Newport, Rhode Island, Restoration and Realty Proposal. Dated September 17, 1968. Cutler Godfrey, Realtor/Edward W. Slater, Architect and Associates, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Fire Insurance Policy for Wetmore Property. Includes title transfer to the Newport Preservation Society, 1969–1970 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Memorandum of congratulations to all employees from F.A. Comstock and a diagram of the Newport Restoration Foundation hierarchy, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - New York Office - office and deductible expenses for August, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Memoranda and correspondence concerning the physical presence at 505 Park Ave., New York City, 1964–1970 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Memoranda and correspondence concerning the physical presence at 505 Park Ave., New York City, 1970–1972 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Bills received at the New York City Office. Includes various invoices for personal effects and office supplies, 1969–1973 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Payment of bills - New York department stores, 1969–1971 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Payment of bills–spirits. Includes receipts for Aidinoff’s and Wellington’s, 1969–1970 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Communication and photocopy regarding traveler's checks, 1974–1975 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Doris Duke Trial Balance–New York Office. Ledger sheets of Assets, Liabilities, and Capital, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Vacation details for the New York Office, 1959-1969 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Memorandum from Harry W. Cox to Doris Duke concerning personnel changes in the New York City Office from March 1969 to September 1970, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence and memoranda regarding various personnel matters including retirements, general salary increases, and letters of recommendation, 1959-1974 (1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence and memoranda regarding various personnel matters including retirements, general salary increases, and letters of recommendation, 1959-1974 (2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Employee's own accounts of business days as requested by Doris Duke. Arranged by week for the period September 29, 1975 through October 17, 1975, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Employee's own accounts of business days as requested by Doris Duke. Arranged by week for the period October 17, 1975 through December 1, 1975, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Dog licenses, vaccination records, 1968–1969 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Various invoices, contracts and proposals for maintenance at Rough Point estate, 1967–1973 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Inventory of items moved from Georgetown, S.C. to Rough Point, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Payment of bills – Rough Point, 1969–1970 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Petty cash for various estates, 1968–1969 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Various receipts for Rough Point estate, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Various invoices for Rough Point estate, including independent contractors, vet bills, and reimbursements, 1967–1975 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Unsolicited requests for unemployment at Rough Point, 1957-1973 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Bills for various maintenance work at Shangri La, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Memorandum from Harry W. Cox to Doris Duke regarding Honolulu invoices for services and merchandise furnished, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and invoices regarding outside equipment, facilities, and materials for Honolulu estate, 1963-1965 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Bills and invoices sent to Doris Duke's Hawaii address, 1970–1973 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence from Johnny Gomez mostly concerning billing for Shangri La, 1963-1967 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Various personnel matters at Shangri La including arrival of married workers from Hong Kong, weekly work reports, and Christmas bonuses, 1965-1974 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence concerning John Gomez's resignation, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence concerning the development of the Solberg Airport, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Receipts and bills of five trips from New Jersey to Newport, R.I. Includes contractors' claims for reimbursement, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Financial documents from Doris Duke's November 1970 trip to Spain, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence regarding Portrait of Marchioness Wellesley With Her Two Sons, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Arrangement of May 9, 1970 trip to Newport, R.I. for Doris Duke, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Statements, refunds, and accounts for American Airlines, Inc., 1973–1975 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence regarding $10,000 gift to Anatolia College from the Doris Duke Foundation, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Letter in support of the Duke Indian Oral History Program from the Arizona State Museum, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Documents related to gift of $10,000 to Bank Street College of Education from Doris Duke, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence regarding gift of $15,000 for Cancer education program at Bloomfield College from Doris Duke, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Documents related to gift of $50,000 to the California Institute of the Arts from Doris Duke, 1970–1971 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Letter informing Doris Duke of the future sale of the Appiani portrait of Napoleon from Christie, Manson & Woods (Christie's Auction House), 1969 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Documents related to a gift of $15,000 for speech laboratory at Clarke School for the Deaf from Doris Duke, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence regarding billing dispute with Detroit Metro Inn (Romulus, MI), 1970 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence regarding tapestries loaned to and subsequently withdrawn from Duke University. Includes declined invitation to football game, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Donation of 22 clothing items to the Education Foundation for the Fashion Industries. Includes detailed description of all items donated, 1971–1972 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Invoices for various services at Shangri La and Falcon Lair, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence concerning shipment of Valentino parcels from Fabius & Co., 1969–1970 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Donation of 144 articles to Fashion Institute of Technology. Includes an appraiser's letter to Cox as well as correspondence from Cox to Doris Duke, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Political donations and correspondence with Fenwick for Congress, 1973–1974 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence regarding tax on purchase from Fernande Desgranges (Paris), 1971 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Letter from Arthur C. Besemer notifying Eaton of retirement from First National City Bank, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Refund and credit for air transportation from Franchino Agency, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Report from Gemological Institute of America concerning examination of jewelry. One necklace and two bracelets verified as natural emeralds, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence regarding donation to Mrs. Hulda Goudie from The General Charitable Aid Association, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence and report outlining concerns raised by Harris, Kerr, Forster & Company over the validity of accounting practices by Ford Property Improvements, a contractor hired by the Newport Preservation Foundation, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence regarding several gifts to the Hillsborough Volunteer Fire Company from Doris Duke, 1970–1972 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence to Horticultural Society of New York regarding request for an appointment with Doris Duke, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence concerning an overcharge dispute with Hotel Prince de Galles (Paris), 1971 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Documents concerning a variety of topics with respect to Walker P. Inman, Jr., including buying and selling of property, bank accounts, travels, Mr. Inman’s principal of assets ledgers, and discussions about Greenfield Plantation. Also includes notable correspondence from Anthony Drexel Duke, 1966-1972 (1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Documents concerning a variety of topics with respect to Walker P. Inman, Jr., including buying and selling of property, bank accounts, travels, Mr. Inman’s principal of assets ledgers, and discussions about Greenfield Plantation. Also includes notable correspondence from Anthony Drexel Duke, 1966-1972 (2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Letter concerning reimbursement for upholstery to the N.Y. Institute of Fine Arts by The Doris Duke Foundation, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Letter to Irving Trust Company regarding check for account KOHANIM, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Letter regarding donation to Jane Pickens Langley for Congress and JPL for Good Government Committee, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence and contract for John Carl Warnecke and Associates, 1963-1965 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Letter to K.D.S. Aviation Limited regarding check from Doris Duke for $5,000, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence regarding gift of $19,000 to Knickerbocker Hospital from Doris Duke, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence to/from Tony Lelli concerning three-piece suit ordered by Ms. Duke, including billing dispute, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Notice of charge account activation from Maison Glass, June 1973. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Receipt of payment for silver dishes from Maison Habis (Beirut), 1972 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Reservation for the Nureyev-Fonteyn Ballet scheduled for June 19, 1975, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Luncheon invitation for October 30 from Laurence S. Rockefeller at Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence regarding charge account information and billing dispute with Mercedes-Benz, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Thank you notes to Metropolitan Museum of Art for various books, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence regarding gifts of stock to Duke Gardens Foundation, Newport Restoration Foundation, and notes and correspondence concerning financial services performed by Morgan Guaranty Trust Company, 1972–1974 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence regarding gift of $12,000 and $350,000 to New York University from Doris Duke, 1970–1971 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence requesting access to facilitate Cliff Walk restoration, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Letter notifying of executed Proxy for Annual Stockholders Meeting of Newport Country Club, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence regarding gifts of $3,000 and $10,000 to Nightingale-Bamford School from Doris Duke, 1970–1973 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence concerning subscription to Orientations Magazine, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence and invoices regarding debate over proper shipping of SEAAC items to New Jersey by Park Travel Agency, Inc. Includes letter from Doris Duke terminating the relationship on December 11, 1972, 1971-1973 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence and invoices pertaining to Parke-Bernet auctions in the Fall of 1969. The September and October auction items involve objects sent to Newport, R.I., 1969 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence outlining the possibility and recourse against a lawsuit by Penson & Company, Inc., the company responsible for packing the dismantled Thai village, 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Letter to Philippe Venet for payment for an unknown item, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 1)